Dustin Irving- Full-Stack Web Developer

613-292-4533 | Ottawa, ON | dustin.irving@gmail.com

dustinirving.com | github.com/dustinirving | linkedin.com/in/dustin-irving

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: JavaScript (ES8), React.js, Context API, HTML5, CSS3, CSS libraries

Backend: Node.js, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, Sequelize, Mongoose

Other: Git Version-Control, RESTful APIs, Agile Scrum Methodology, MVC Framework, Data

Structures and Algorithms, JEST, Mobile-first design, PWAs, and more

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with a certificate in Web Development from Trilogy's Coding Bootcamp at Carleton University and a Bachelor of Science with a Specialization in Biochemistry from the University of Ottawa. Exceptional problem solving skills, able to thrive in a team environment and a strong desire to learn.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Vogi Jun 2020 - Present

Live: vogi.ca | Repo: github.com/dustinirving/vogi

- Vogi is a non-profit organization that allows other organizations and volunteers to connect and work on projects together to mutually benefit
- Roles: UI Design, State Management with React.js, API routing, JEST, MongoDB
- Tech Stack: React.js, AntDesign, Node.js, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB

Travelbook May 2020 - Jun 2020

Live: travel-book.ca | Repo: github.com/dustinirving/travel-book

- Full-stack application that allows users to create an account, post about their travel experiences, update their profile and connect with nearby travellers
- Roles: RESTful APIs, EJS templating, Semantic UI responsiveness
- Tech Stack: Semantic UI, EJS, Node.js, Express, Sequelize, MySQL

COVID-19 Tracker Mar 2020 - Apr 2020

Live: lagbana.github.io/covid19-tracker/ | Repo: github.com/dustinirving/covid19-tracker

- Displays the latest data regarding cases of COVID-19 in the form of a graph and provides the user with the most recent news updates related to the virus
- Roles: API calls to fetch the data, manipulate the data to be displayed in the graph
- Tech Stack: MaterializeCSS, HTML5, JavaScript, Chart.js, COVID-19 API, NYT API

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cook The Royal Oak | Ottawa, ON | Dec 2019 - Present

- Prepared and cooked food in a fast-paced, high intensity work environment
- Acquired knowledge to provide outstanding customer service
- Developed teamwork collaboration and cooperation skills

ESL Teacher CL Education Center | Changwon, South Korea | Nov 2018- Nov 2019

- Taught English as a second language to kindergarten and elementary school students
- Developed curriculums and organized a variety of events for the children
- Gained confidence, enhanced interpersonal skills, while promoting self growth

EDUCATION

Trilogy's Coding Bootcamp Carleton University | Feb 2020 - July 2020

- Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development
- A+ Average

Bachelor of Science University of Ottawa | Sep 2012 - Apr 2016

- Specialization in Biochemistry
- \$2000 Entrance Scholarship